Patrik Fuhrmann, Software Engineer

Experienced software engineer with main interests in distributed systems. Currently specialising in PHP and MySQL driven systems, and recently exploring Go language as a future career endeavour. I possess full fluency in JavaScript and familiarity with Node.js and NoSQL backends. Furthermore, my in-depth knowledge of the cloud system management allows me to perform administration on various servers. Lastly, in my leadership experience, I was in charge of software development teams and responsible for the technical delivery of web properties.

 ☑ Email: contact@patrikfuhrmann.com Availability: 2 months notice

> Website: https://patrikfuhrmann.com

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Specialties: LEMP / LAMP, writing OO code, Methodologies: Agile (Scrum & Kanban), BDD developing and interfacing with REST APIs, SQL (Behaviour-driven development), TDD profiling and optimization

Languages: PHP (6 years), Golang (6 months), Node.js (2 years), HTML / CSS (6 years), JavaScript Tycoon, MongoDB

(6 years)

Tools: Symfony / Laravel PHP frameworks, Git, Java / Android, C# / .NET

JSON, PHPUnit / Behat / Mink, ORM, MVC

(Test-driven development)

Databases: MySQL, Redis, PostgreSQL, Kyoto

Other notable programming skills:

RECENT EMPLOYMENT

May 2017 - Present, London

Senior Software Engineer (PHP, Golang) | Mercari Europe, London

- Largest mobile marketplace in Japan with over 60 million downloads worldwide

October 2016 - April 2017, London

Web Engineer | Cloudflare

- The web security company, covering roughly 10% of internet traffic at the time
- Part of the larger group of engineers in the front-facing team using scrum
- Creating and maintaining APIs with lot of traffic (1 billion+ reg/month)
- Developed WebP API integration with the Cloudflare's edge systems
- Various improvements to the internal "page rules" engine
- Working with many technologies such as Docker, Kyoto Tycoon, Redis etc.
- Server-side work on the scaling of the PostgreSQL database (master/slave replication)

February 2015 - September 2016, London

Technical Lead | babylon health

- Largest doctor-on-demand startup in the UK
- Started as lead PHP developer and promoted after 10 months to the tech lead
- Heading technical efforts of the Predictive Analytics team
- Responsible for the hiring of new engineers i.e. PHP, python and data scientists
- Creating development standards and best practices followed across the team
- Building out the architecture to support the delivery of the AI Predictive Analytics platforms
- Onboarding and mentoring engineers to ensure quality and timely delivery

March 2014 - January 2015, London

Senior PHP Developer (Symfony) | LendInvest

- LendInvest is leading online lender for short-term property finance
- Transforming legacy code from Codelgniter to Symfony2 framework
- Creating BDD (Behavior-Driven Development) testing suite using Behat 3
- Redeveloped systems were successfully launched in December 2014 which allowed company eventually lower minimum investment amount to £1,000

January 2013 – December 2013, London

Senior Software Engineer (Node.js, PHP) | entrago

- Early-stage startup, celebrity channels for fans
- Working with sizeable Redis database (100+ GB)
- Mostly using Node.js but also PHP (ZF2)

December 2011 - September 2012, Reading

PHP Developer | Primrose.co.uk

- One of the largest UK online gardening retailer
- Finding bottlenecks in performance by profiling PHP. As a result, we went from 1600+ SQL queries on each page to less than 400 per page

EDUCATION

2012 - 2015

BEng (Hons) Software Engineering | University of Greenwich, London

- 1st class honours degree
- Dissertation: Software Design Patterns in the NFC Android Development

HOBBIES

Traveling, reading about technology, skiing and also water sports.